[Zene]
Hey Joe. Hey. "What's this all about then? Well
we have a problem and it's a very big problem,
and unfortunately most people aren't aware of it.
It doesn't matter what your personal views are,
your politics, your religion or where you are,
and once you see the problem you can't unsee
it. It's like a one-way door. But thankfully we
also have the solution and it's this solution
that I'm so passionate about sharing and it's
what makes me just so optimistic for the future.
The challenge I find though is how can anybody
fully value a solution unless they understand what
the problem is. And so, I put this presentation
together for some friends and it assumes no
knowledge other than just being a human being with
some life experience and they encouraged me then
to make this presentation into a video so I can
share it with everyone. So, I hope you enjoy.
Welcome to 'What's The Problem?'. So, what is the
problem? Too many unfortunately. I probably could
have written twice as many things down on this
slide. I think we all have that sense of unease;
we all feel internally that things are not
moving in the right direction in our lives,
in the world. Things are becoming harder not
easier, and I think for most of us we would
recognize some elements of these things on
the screen as touching our lives directly,
or indirectly, and what I'm here today to
show you is that all these things may seem
unconnected but they're really not. The primary
cause of all of these is the quality of our money.
Now, we're going to do this through a story.
So, imagine there's this far off world where
you have hundreds of smart people traveling on
a ship and this ship gets wrecked on a deserted
island. This deserted island is so far from
everywhere else they're effectively cut off,
but the island is resource rich - it has
everything they could possibly need to
rebuild society. Because these people have come
from an advanced civilization they know exactly
where they're ultimately going to get back to
but now, they're starting again with nothing.
What's also clear is that they need some way
of trading with each other once they start to
rebuild so they prioritize deciding on what
to use for their new money. And suspend your
disbelief slightly further, in that they have,
despite not having anything, the ability to create
whatever monetary system they want with whatever
characteristics. So the first question they need
to answer is - what makes good money? There are
seven things. So these guys have the ability
to create whatever they want so instead of just
creating good money they create the perfect money.
The perfect money is scarce which means it
has a fixed Supply forever and is instantly
and costlessly verifiable by everybody.
So if everybody can check it whenever
they want at no cost then you can verify for
yourself that nobody's creating any extra.
It needs to be portable so you can effortlessly
move and store it with negligible costs.
It needs to be divisible, and the perfect
money would be infinitely divisible.
It needs to be durable - it can't rot or go off.
It can't deteriorate. So the
perfect money exists forever.
It's fungible which means every piece is
forever the same as every other piece.
It needs to be acceptable so everyone
anywhere can both send and receive.
And the really important one
is it needs to be censorship
resistant - you hold it yourself.
Nobody can take it away from you
without your permission and no one
can stop you sending or receiving.
So this is great, they decide on perfect money.
But then there's a disagreement. Two leaders
emerge from within the population. The first,
Satoshi, he says, "Well, given these are the
characteristics of perfect money, that's going
to be true today, true tomorrow and true forever,
so we should lock them in, and you should
never change. Whereas Fiatello - he says,
"Well I get that. I get these characteristics of
perfect money and I totally agree *but* what if
there's an emergency? What if we need to change
something? What if the people we put in charge of
our money feel like it's not working and need
to make an adjustment? I think we should have
the perfect money, but we should also have a Big
Red Button which allows someone to press it and
change any of the characteristics if we need to.
Of course, no one ever will, but just in case."
This becomes an irreconcilable
disagreement so a fairly drastic solution,
but they build a huge wall right
down the middle of this island. On
one side they create the currency called
Satoshis, which is perfect money always,
and on the other side are Fiatellos, which is
perfect money but with the option to change it.
Now this wall is so big it cuts off the
communication and the trade between both
sides on the island so effectively
they're cut off from one another.
So to begin with nobody has anything on either
side of the island so everyone's starting from
zero. Initially people have to be self-sufficient
- each person is fishing for their food,
cutting down trees for their wood to make fires
and also for houses, and they're also building
their own shelters. Now even though they have
perfect money there's very limited trading here
because people are working hard just to satisfy
their day-to-day needs across all of these goods.
But people are different. Some people are better
at some things than others and so people quickly
realize that if I spend my time focusing on the
things I'm good at and reducing the amount of time
I spend on things that I'm poor at then I can
contribute more to society. I can increase the
amount of goods I can provide to society in the
same amount of time as the average person. So the
wood cutter spends all his time now cutting down
wood. He stops fishing, he stops building shelters
and because he's spending his time cutting down
wood, he increases the quantity of wood available
to everyone else versus three people spending a
third of their time each because he's good at it.
Not only does the increase in the quantity
of wood available reduce the price of wood
for everybody on the island the quality
is also higher - he's better at doing it.
He produces a higher quality output, so prices
fall and quality increases. And not only that,
he's not the only wood cutter, there are
multiple wood cutters, so they're all
competing to supply wood to everybody else
and they're competing on price and in terms
of quality. And now what happens is because
the wood cutter needs other goods to survive,
he has to sell the wood to buy fish, he has
to sell the wood to pay for the services of
the home builder. So now everybody is
actively trading in this perfect money.
Because processes continue to improve the wood
cutter can now satisfy the needs of the rest
of the population for wood in a smaller amount
of time. He can then take that time and think
about his own processes, his own Innovations,
maybe he can make cutting down wood even more
efficient and if he does that it drives
prices lower, it drives quality higher.
Maybe he reaches the end of his Innovation within
his wood cutting and then uses the excess money
and excess capital he has to invest in other
people. Maybe he lends it to the fisherman
who then builds a boat to increase the amount
of fish the fisherman can catch for everybody.
So, what happens over time in a
free market with perfect money:
*prices go down forever and
quality goes up forever*.
So what people see on both sides of the island is
that the purchasing power of their money starts
to increase. Goods cost less tomorrow than they
do today so the price of tomorrow is lower. The
purchasing power of both currencies is increasing
at about 3% a year and this lifts the quality of
life. Life becomes cheaper and cheaper over time
for everybody, not just those people who are most
productive in society. But the key thing is *the
money itself is becoming more valuable over time*.
That is, until these guys come along.
So now because the society is growing
and the population's growing both sides
of the island elect a government. Now it
doesn't matter if the government
is left or right, big, small, up,
down doesn't matter they are all
the same - when it comes to this.
However well-run the government is, inevitably it
will hit a deficit at some point and that means
it's spending more than it's receiving.
That could be through mismanagement,
but it could just be through external circumstance
like a natural disaster, or something like this.
The causes are not important, but it will
happen over the course of time, inevitably.
But now we see a divergence across both
sides of the island. Satoshi - he only has
two choices here. To balance the budget, he
needs to either raise taxes or cut spending,
or maybe a combination of
the two. Whereas Fiatello,
he has exactly the same choices...
but he also has a Big Red Button.
The important thing here is they're both
up for re-election and Fiatello knows that
if he raises taxes or he cuts spending it's
going to cost him votes. So, just this time,
he decides to press The Big Red Button and print
a little bit of extra money for the government.
Okay, so what are the consequences? Well,
for Satoshi - not great. He cannot hide
those changes from the population because they're
paying more in taxes or they're getting less back
from the government from its spending, so he
loses the election. But government reduces in
size naturally so now overall the efficiency in
the economy has increased but not only this - the
social balance is improved within the economy
because people now realize there is no free money.
Taxes need to balance spending. But the important
thing is prices continue to fall
and quality continues to increase.
Now for Fiatello - great news, he gets re-elected
and to start with it's consequence
free. He thinks this is the greatest
thing ever - I get re-elected and there's
no downside... but something's changed.
So, what's happened? Fiatello's
pressed The Big Red Button
which has printed some money for the
government which has debased the currency.
So, what does that mean? He's increased the
amount of money in the economy overnight,
but he hasn't increased the amount
of goods and services available in
the economy overnight so now there's
more Fiatellos washing around compared
to yesterday for each piece
of the goods and services.
This has three major impacts; the first is
a distortion of price signals, the second
is that increases input costs for businesses,
and the third - it leads to asset inflation.
That first one, distorting price signals,
well, prior to Fiatello pressing The Big
Red Button here all price changes in the
economy were purely a function of demand
and supply because this was a free market
with perfect money. But what's happened now
is that money has entered the economy, not to
everybody equally or even in proportion to the
amount of money everybody holds. The money
has entered the economy via the government.
It enters via the government into the accounts
of companies and people connected directly or
indirectly to the government. So, what Fiatello
starts to see is price increases in certain parts
of the economy. The the signal to everybody else
in the economy is that there's an imbalance of
supply and demand just in these sectors. So
you see a misallocation of capital by the
entrepreneurs in the market caused by the money
printer but not only that, it's human capital,
it's smart people, it's active people who
are trying to be productive - they get
sucked in closer to the government and
not servicing the rest of the economy.
The second is that business input costs increase.
Now every single business in Fiatello's country
has at least a human being and some raw
material inputs like energy or even some
harder raw materials. Because the costs of
these things have gone up these businesses
now need to try and change something about
their product to maintain the small profit
margins that ensure that they can continue in
business. The first and most obvious one is
just to pass on the price increase to the
customer. The second is to keep the price
the same and the quality the same but just
shrink the product so instead of having 100
grams it's now 90 grams but for the same price.
Or the third one is to reduce the input costs.
This is where consumer inflation
comes from. This is the only source of
consumer inflation - is the money printer,
causing businesses to make these changes.
But if a business passes on the price increase
outright, or it shrinks the product and the
customer now just needs to buy more of it to
satisfy the fact that they needed 100 grams not 90
grams, both of those things reduce affordability.
So the population is becoming poorer. They're
going to have less disposable income despite
buying the same as what they bought yesterday.
If instead, the business chooses to keep
the price the same, the size the same,
but just reduce the cost, the most obvious
thing to do is just to fire people which leads
to unemployment. Now there are fewer people with
jobs which reduces the overall affordability for
the population in Fiatello's world. But not
only that, now the government's got a second
issue it needs to solve - how does it help support
all these people who are recently unemployed?
But the most insidious way is for companies
to reduce their input *quality* and so what
Fiatello starts to see is there's a rise
in obesity across the population because
the food that was previously fresh and had high
quality ingredients is replaced with ever lower
quality ingredients and more industrialized
sludge. This leads to obesity; it also leads
to a myriad of secondary health issues which
causes a Health crisis and now the government
has to step in and figure out how it needs to
support all these people who are now unhealthy.
The third is asset inflation. Since
Fiatello pressed The Big Red Button
asset prices have been going up. The stock
market goes higher and higher and higher,
house prices go higher and higher and higher.
He thinks, "I'm some sort of economic genius".
But they're going up in price because he's just
created more Fiatellos, so anybody who knows that
there are more Fiatellos in the system of course
wouldn't sell their asset for the same as they did
yesterday. They would take into account the fact
that there were just more Fiatellos in the system,
so this is what is driving these prices up. But
this asset increase is good for the people who own
the assets but not for the people who don't. He
has a wealth inequality begin to emerge across the
economy and not just that, because house prices
are now more expensive the rent is more expensive.
So he sees increased levels of homelessness
and this increased levels of homelessness,
guess what, requires more government intervention
to try and deal with. Now asset prices are flying,
the stock market's on fire, the prevailing
perception across the population is,
"Why would I not invest? Why would I just keep
the money? I should be buying the stock market,
I should be invested, I should be buying a second
home to rent out, I should be buying speculative
assets because they never go down, they just
go up. If I don't invest, I'm a fool." Because
the assets are going up the banks are pushing
ever more leverage for people. Pushing bigger
and bigger mortgages to individuals, loans to
companies but now that house prices have gone up
and now that everyone has more debt, at the same
time as families are struggling with affordability
of day-to-day life, it's now much harder to
buy a house. So families where previously
they could have one main earner and afford
to buy a house with a mortgage can't anymore.
You now need both parents working. Both parents
working to afford the mortgage and afford to live,
and when that happens people spend less time
together. You start to see the breakdown of
the nuclear family. They spend less time with
their children. They can afford to have fewer
children. now because you have declining
birth rates Fiatello starts to see a change
in his demographics across the population.
Fewer children are being born whereas the
older generations are living longer, and he
now starts to realize that the promises he
made to these older generations about being
able to retire at a certain age or having a
good quality of life, or defined income, in
their retirement can't be delivered upon.
For those not lucky enough to be able to
buy a house who are maybe stuck renting,
whereas before they could think about renting
the same place for 3 years or 5 years - because
the rent goes up too much every year, now
they're thinking about one year maybe two
years. You're planning less for the future
maybe you're putting off getting married,
putting off having children. You start to
prioritize today at the expense of tomorrow.
People see that saving their Fiatellos never gets
them anywhere because the asset prices are going
up too quickly - they'll never be able to buy a
house. So if you'll never be able to buy a house
then prioritize 'living your best life' and going
on holiday and spending more, enjoying yourself.
But for those not fortunate to be in this
position for those that every day has a struggle,
feeding themselves and their families, housing
themselves and their families - they're stuck
on a treadmill of decline. Every day is
harder which leads to a growth in addiction,
various forms of addiction, including
opioids across Fiatello's Island which
leads to yet more of a Health crisis and
yet more intervention from the government.
And all of this leads to a mental
health crisis across the population.
Now the government finds itself in a position
where because it pressed The Big Red Button it's
created a whole range of secondary issues that now
it needs to step in and try and solve. Because it
has to step in and try and solve these things it
means the government needs to divert more capital
to these areas of the economy which, again, is a
greater misallocation of capital which pulls more
entrepreneurs into the wrong parts of the economy
through the distortion of the price signals.
Between the increased leverage in the
economy driven by the Banks and the
misallocation of capital it sows the seeds
of the next emergency... and Fiatello has
only one choice - and that's to
press The Big Red Button again!
Now he's starting to realize that
actually this wasn't consequence free.
Now he's lurching from crisis to ever bigger
crisis. He presses The Big Red Button which
debases the currency, which leads to bigger
government and more involvement in everything.
And now not only is the government bigger
but the government has spawned a series
of parasitic Industries attached to
it. Big Pharma who are increasingly
involved with the government to
try to deal with the symptoms,
but not the causes, of the various Health
Crises. Never incentivized is to actually
cure a patient just to treat them long term
because a healthy customer is a lost customer.
Big Food pushes for ever lower
food standards across the economy.
The Military-Industrial Complex pushes for ever
greater spending on defence both
at home and on foreign shores.
Wall Street are up to their eyeballs in debt
and now so leveraged that the government wants
to protect them. They can't be allowed
to fail - because if the banks fail,
the population loses their
money, the government falls.
The government also continues to
make unproductive investments.
Investments trying to deal with the
secondary issues it's created but
also investments driven from whatever
political ideology the government has.
All of these things are effectively now *crony
corporatism*. It's very hard to see where the
government ends, and these industries begin. The
success of the government is deeply intertwined
with the success of the industries. These
industries start to ask the government to
become regulated. "You need to regulate us to
protect the public". But this regulation all
it does is make competition harder. The one,
two, three companies in each of these areas
and now very very close to the government.
They supply the people for the regulator,
when the regulators end their tenure, they go
back and work for these companies. It stops
smaller companies coming in and competing with
them to then supply the government on better
terms with higher quality product. So quality
starts to decline and prices start to rise which,
of course, is great news for these
companies because profit margins go up.
What happens then is the media gets captured.
The government is teetering to maintain social
stability. It's now protecting these industries
at the expense of the population rather than
the other way around and because of this social
balance that it needs to maintain it can't allow
Free Speech, dissent, alternative
opinions or questioning of anything
that undermines the legitimacy of the
government in anyway. Not only that,
the biggest advertisers for the media companies
are companies connected to the government,
so the media companies increasingly
don't want to upset their advertisers.
When you have a captured media and a military
industrial complex fomenting strife on foreign
shores you get the creation of the Forever
Wars. And the wars themselves are actively
supported by the Fiatello
population because all they
see in their media is that "we have to do
this because it's the right thing to do."
And, between the Forever Wars and the banking
system bailouts and the excessive debt it leads
to the next emergency but this time it's just
so much bigger, and the only choice he has is
to press The Big Red Button again. But this
time it's different. It's a massive erosion
of trust. Every time he presses the button more
and more people become aware of what is happening,
and this goes round and round
and round until something breaks.
And now Fiatello is starting to get quite worried.
So what's happening to the money? Well, instead
of increasing 3% a year in purchasing power he's
now losing 7% a year because he's printing
10% a year of extra money. Not only that,
he's undermining the productivity in the
economy by distorting all the price signals.
So what happens to the Fiatello island population?
Well, the poor who are on fixed
wages, have very low-income security
and no assets - they can't win. They
just get poorer every single year.
For the middle earners, who have fixed salaries
and mixed income security - they're not the
first to be fired - they often have a home,
but they can never sell the home and realize
any gain because you've got to live somewhere,
if you sell one home you've got to buy another
home. You might have some Investments,
but they are becoming the new poor.
Well surely the wealthy are doing well?
Their income is largely from asset yields
from operating businesses or investing. Their
income security is high because they can't get
fired but for them it's death-by-a-thousand-cuts.
They see their wealth as a number continue to
increase but they feel like they're getting
poorer. Life continues to get harder and
that's because the rate at which they're
earning money, their yield on their assets,
is below the rate which Fiatello is printing
money so they're slowly having their wealth
siphoned away by the politically connected.
Those that are government funded and have fully
insulated income security and, perversely,
their income goes up and becomes even more
valuable as society continues to decline because
the government needs more and more intervention.
It's really just industrialized theft at
this point from everyone else in society.
But now so much time has passed that the wall
down the middle of the island starts to crack,
and it starts to crack in such
a way that both people and money
can start to flow from one side to the other.
So, on the one side you've got the Satoshis
increasing their purchasing power at 3% a year,
on the other side you've got the Fiatellos
that are losing 7% purchasing power every year.
So, what happens and why?
What Fiatello starts to see is that
money and people start to leave
because they don't trust their ability to
save using Fiatellos, they want Satoshis.
Okay, so this sums it up: on a Fiatello
standard your money is stealing from you
whereas on a Satoshi standard the whole world is
working 24/7 to increase your purchasing power.
But now the Escape valve is open. People
realize they can't save in Fiatellos so
they start selling Fiatellos to buy Satoshis,
so the Fiatellos decline further in value,
triggering yet more budgetary and currency
crises for Fiatello to deal with... and the
only choice is to press The Big Red Button
again! But this time printing money is not
enough because value is leaking out of Fiatello's
side of the island. He needs to change another
characteristic of perfect money which is to
remove the censorship resistant nature of it.
The Fiatello population used to be
able to hold the money themselves,
now Fiatello says you're no longer allowed to hold
it yourselves. You have to put it in the banks.
The banks are going to hold everybody's money.
The population now feel that they are guilty
until proven innocent for making any transaction -
the banks will check every transaction to 'protect
you' which means when people are trying to
buy certain things, including Satoshis the
banks now say "No... it's because of this,
it's because of that, it's because of the
other". He restricts the flow of capital out of
Fiatello's side of the island. He may even just
create explicit capital controls - "You're now
no longer allowed to buy Satoshis at all". But
people always find a way and more and more people
are waking up to what is happening, and the cycle
continues. The important thing is the wealth,
and the people flee to the uncorrupted money.
Now Fiatello is beginning to really panic
So where does it end for Fiatello? Well, if
he's lucky, with sustained inflation allowing
the government to inflate away its debts and
slowly siphon away the wealth of the public.
This may even border on hyperinflation.
I say "lucky" because it's very hard to
do that and maintain social cohesion
and something is likely to go wrong.
It will *definitely* be asset seizures. Now
that all the money is held in the banks one
day Fiatello will decree that "we're all in
it together" and the banks will hand over a
proportion of that capital to the government.
Just like in Cyprus in 2013 - if you held over
€100,000 in the bank, overnight 45% of
that went to the government. The public
was effectively bailed in to bailout the banks
and the government from their own mismanagement.
It also happened in the US in 1933. They made
gold holdings for the individual illegal,
and this lasted for almost 40 years. If you
held more than $100 of gold and you were caught:
$10,000 fine or 10 years in prison, and this
was when $10,000 was a *huge* amount of money.
Fiatello sees a rise in political extremism
on both ends of the spectrum. The government
never explains to the population where these
problems are coming from. They don't tell
them it's because of the money printing
via The Big Red Button. They control the
media. The government is protective of
itself. They don't tell the population
the truth. They don't help the population
join the dots. They don't explain the link
from The Big Red Button to the issues. They
blame it on the 'greedy businessmen' or 'the
billionaires' or 'that foreign dictator'
or this or that. Then what happens is,
people ask for more help and more support from the
government to deal with all of these issues and so
the only solution is the government's involved
in everything. At every step of this journey
the solution to all the problems has always been
*more government involvement* and so the people
see these problems and vote for more government
involvement to solve them... or something worse.
But in all scenarios people want
to hold Satoshis and not Fiatellos.
So if we go back to that list of seven
characteristics of perfect money - Fiatello
only changed two of them. The other five are
still exactly the same and look where he ended up.
Now the reveal (and some of
you may be slightly ahead of
me here). The US Dollar is just a
terrible version of the Fiatello.
The US Dollar is corrupted on
the same two key issues that
the Fiatellos were but on the other
five it's materially worse as well.
In terms of portability - it's easy to carry,
easy to pay but it's not great for merchants.
You pay instantly but the merchant doesn't get
the money for multiple days and that's
if there was no fraud or chargebacks.
It's divisible but only to a point and removes
the ability to do microtransactions which will
unlock potentially completely
different economic models.
It's durable, in digital form, but we have a cash
component, and that cash component is constantly
undermined. The notes are reprinted in terms
of design every 15 or 20 years so there's no
ability for an individual to save outside the
banking system. If you put notes under your bed
or under the floorboards and leave them 25 years
they're worthless. Those types of notes have
gone out of circulation, so you need to take the
notes every 15 or 20 years to the bank hand them
in and get new notes. They recentralize
everything periodically, out of choice.
They're fungible which means every dollar is
the same as every other dollar... until it's
not. Some countries around the world
have already introduced what are known
as CBDCs - which is central bank digital
currency, but effectively it's programmable
money. A specific dollar may have an expiration
date - you need to spend it before this period
of time elapses or else it disappears.
Or a dollar may have only specific use
cases - you must spend this dollar on X or
Y, or you must not spend this dollar on ABC.
The Dollar is very acceptable around the
world, but you can't pay with it everywhere
and typically most national currencies
are only acceptable in their own country.
And the US has a major Fiatello problem.
This is the budget for 2024 - the budget not the
actuals which of course were worse -a deficit of
almost $2 trillion on a spend just over $6
trillion. That's a loss in one year. Now to
put that in context they'd have to double
the amount of individual income taxes for
everybody in the US just to balance that
and on the cost side they can make some
improvements but there are some key things there
you just cannot remove like the debt interest.
And the consequences? Well, this is a chart of
the amount of money in the system in dollars
and the amount of debt issued by the US government
over time. Now I've labelled 1971 on here because
that's when the US came unilaterally off the
gold standard. Prior to 1971 you could give
your dollars back and receive gold in return.
Nixon took the US off the gold standard and
every currency in the world followed and since
then it's allowed the US to print unlimited
amounts of money to satisfy its own needs. The red
chart on the left-hand axis shows that amount of
money is now $22 trillion and on the right hand
side you've got the US government debt which,
even a month later, this chart is now
out of date - it's now $36 trillion!
And this doesn't include the unfunded
liabilities - the amount of money the
US government has committed to pay at some
point in the future through Social Security,
Medicare, Medicaid etc but it hasn't had
to write the cheque yet. Now depending on
how you calculate that it's between $50 and
$200 trillion, on top of 36 trillion of debt!
The only way to solve that is more
money printing. The money printer
is systematically destroying the
purchasing power of the Dollar.
Now you may think I have something against
the Dollar. I absolutely don't! The Dollar
is the *best* that we have. I would love
to be able to use the Dollar, as would the
vast majority of people around the world but
unfortunately most people just aren't as lucky.
This is the performance of all the
other currencies versus the Dollar
over the last 10 years. Some have near enough
disappeared completely and some absolutely have,
they've ceased to exist. The
people who saved their economic
energy in those currencies have seen them vanish.
The unfortunate reality here as the
wonderful Lyn Alden repeatedly says
Is "Nothing Stops This Train". There is no way out
for governments. The only solution is
to keep pressing The Big Red Button.
And so, the conclusion is a quote from Hayek
who was an economist of the Austrian School,
"The history of government management
of money has except for a few short
happy periods been one of incessant fraud
and deception." And he said this in 1988.
Now, that would all be pretty depressing if
there wasn't a solution but thankfully there is.
The only solution here is *the separation of money
and state*. The government cannot be
allowed access to a Big Red Button.
And Hayek again and this time the quote is
from 1984. "I don't believe we shall ever
have good money again until we take
it out of the hands of government,
we can't take it violently out of their
hands. All we can do is by some sly,
roundabout way introduce something
they just can't stop". Brilliant quote.
So, I hope now with these links
between The Big Red Button and
the money printer and all of these
issues that we see in our lives today
that it's now much clearer that if we
can fix the money we'll fix the world.
The good news here, and this is the best news,
is that Satoshis are real and
even Fiatello is now a convert.
The solution is Bitcoin.
One Bitcoin is 100 million Satoshis
in the same way that $1 is 100 cents
Now, you may feel you know about Bitcoin already
because of something you've been told
by friends or you read in the media.
I would encourage you to start again.
When we derive our information from the
media or from people who have derived
their information from the media, and that media
is connected to the people who own and benefit
from the money printer, it tends not to be
necessarily the most accurate information.
So don't trust, verify.
Come to SatsVsFiat.com - we've set up
a website which helps people get up and
running. If you're just getting started,
maybe even never heard of Bitcoin before,
come sign up and we'll send you some
information so you can learn about
it for yourself and make your
own decisions about Bitcoin.
If you're further along and maybe even call
yourself a Bitcoin already then amazing.
This is not a commercial enterprise
for me, this is a charitable one,
and so any support from within the Bitcoin
Community, or from further afield, I would
love to receive. If people want to give this talk
themselves to their friends or just share it more
broadly or even volunteer to give a presentation
as part of our group, then just get in touch.
And the third one is inviting us to
speak - we want as many people as
possible to see this presentation because
the information contained within it about
what the problem is is so important. So
we'd love to speak, if you'll have us,
at schools, universities,
industry conferences, events,
even at workplaces if people are interested
to learn more. So please just get in touch.
Here's the QR code which will take you directly
to the website. Alternatively, if you are on
X and want to come and say hi and join the
conversation with us then please, please do.
Firstly, thank you for watching. I hope
you enjoyed it. Please share this with
anyone you care about. And, if there's
one thing that you take away from this is
I hope you will remember that: if we fix the
money, we'll fix the world thank you [Music]